<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Come Away With Me</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://come-away-with.me/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://come-away-with.me/</id><updated>2013-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>La Paz</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2013/March/la-paz.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2013-03-24:2013/March/la-paz.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mid January&amp;nbsp;2013&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a surprise when we arrived, after passing the traffic jam to reach the pay tall gate,
to see the city below us in a valley. The road took a big turn down and it felt like sinking
down between houses, slowly. There were buildings everywhere, on each side of the&amp;nbsp;mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus dropped us in the center, and we walked to our hostel we booked ahead, Hostal Republica,
which wasn&amp;#8217;t in the main touristy part, but behind all the official government buildings. A bit
expensive, but from what we heard we were happy to have a nice hostel since it&amp;#8217;s not always the
case in La&amp;nbsp;Paz.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail" style="margin-bottom:1em"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5711-GX1B5719.jpg" alt="City of La Paz from mirador Killi Killi"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;City of La Paz from mirador Killi Killi&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail" style="margin-bottom:1em"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5672.jpg" alt="Too much stuff!"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Too much stuff!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;div class="span7 offset1"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Spanish couple we met in Cusco, made us rethink about our luggage. They had only 10/13kg each.
Of course they didn&amp;#8217;t have a tent, mats, cooking stove and utensils, but nevertheless we decided
to cut through our bag&amp;#8217;s weight. We couldn&amp;#8217;t move anymore with our +20kg each. We spent half a day putting on
the bed everything we had and deciding what will go back home, to the trash, or stay with us.
And it&amp;#8217;s with pride that we went to the post office under a heavy rainy day, to send back home a bit
over 10kg! No kidding! Books, clothes, Spanish courses, knifes (none of them made it because
it&amp;#8217;s not allowed to send them by post in Bolivia, the knifes) and more stuff. It&amp;#8217;s wasn&amp;#8217;t
very cheap but we were so relief to have lighter backpacks. I could almost put it on my shoulder with
only one arm, almost&amp;#8230; And of course, the box we went to look after in shops, they didn&amp;#8217;t want it but
you had to buy their one!&amp;nbsp;Extortion!&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day before shipping back home our box, we went to see the mirador (lookout) of the city and on
the way back to the hostel, the rain starting to be very heavy and very close to us so we decided to
go and hide for a coffee. By miracle, when we sat I saw a flyer about the e-reader I was looking for
in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; before leaving, which I couldn&amp;#8217;t find. They were selling it, so I jumped on and bought it.
So now, I have a light book of the rest of the trip. I was so happy! It&amp;#8217;s definitively a best companion for&amp;nbsp;travels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other days in La Paz, we relaxed, went out to the touristy part of town to organize the following weeks in South
Bolivia: Sucre and Uyuni. We just bought a bus ticket to Sucre and will see there if it gets cheaper
for the&amp;nbsp;salars.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                         &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5682.jpg" alt="Streets"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Streets&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5685.jpg" alt="Official building"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Official building&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5688.jpg" alt="Busy street, as most of them"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Busy street, as most of them&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5705.jpg" alt="Need to fix something at home?"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Need to fix something at home?&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Lake Titicaca</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2013/March/lake-titicaca.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2013-03-24:2013/March/lake-titicaca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beginning of January&amp;nbsp;2013&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;#8217;t manage to make the trip to Copacabana, Bolivia, in one day from Cusco because the bus arrived
with 2 hours of delay in Puno, at 16:00. And the last bus for Copacabana was leaving at 15:30. So we
spent the night in Puno, with the Danish couple we met in Cusco going in the same direction as&amp;nbsp;us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We skept the Uros (floating island), because it just became a tourist trap. Next morning, 7:30, our
bus was leaving for Copacabana. Two hours later we were at the border, where we had to queue 20 minutes
to get the stamp of the Peruvian immigration, before going to the police office to get the exit stamp.
Then we had to walked to the Bolivian side to get the entrance paper and stamp pretty quickly. One
thing we discovered, is that there won&amp;#8217;t be many American tourists since they must pay more than &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;$100
to enter Bolivia. It&amp;#8217;s what you call &amp;#8220;reciprocal visa fee&amp;#8221;, welcome! Back on the bus, we were in Copacabana
a bit more than one hour&amp;nbsp;later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program was to spent 3 nights in town to relax, enjoy the lake and decide what we would do next.
We stayed at the Hotel El Mirador with a great view other the lake, after discussing the price because,
yeah, I forgot to tell you about something. Leaving Cusco we made a little catch-up budget plan on our
travel costs after checking our spending in each countries so far and where we should be at. Of course,
there was a gap! Not huge, but not small neither. So, until the end of March, we will be (or should I say
&amp;#8220;try&amp;#8221;) to leave with us$40 per day for both of us. That sounds feasible in Bolivia, but I really don&amp;#8217;t know
how it will be in Argentina and Chile. We&amp;#8217;ll see!&amp;nbsp;Ojala!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also started to take our medicines we bought in Lima for the stomach because our digestion process was
going up and down every day and we still didn&amp;#8217;t feel very good since a long time. It was about time to
cleaned it&amp;nbsp;up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading books, updating the website design, writing some texts and emails, sleeping, eating, walking around.
3 days later we can advise to skip all restaurant down on the beach side, they are the worse. On the 2nd night,
we were very happy to see the tropical rain coming for once, so that the people playing super loud music on
the beach out of a pickup&amp;#8217;s trunk would finally leave, at&amp;nbsp;00:30/01:00.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we set off on a boat to go to the north part of Isla del Sol, Challapampa, to spend one night there.
We were happy to find a not too expensive room in town looking out to the cordillera with magnificent 6000/7000m
summits. On the next day we walked from North to South on the ridge line, waiting until the morning rain was
almost other before leaving our&amp;nbsp;room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Yumani after 3 good hours, taking time to take pictures, where we were a bit sad to already have
booked our bus ticket to La Paz. The view from the summit of the village is just amazing. We stopped for a nice
lunch on a terrace with a huge view of the lake. We sat there until we had to get down to catch the afternoon boat
back to Copacabana. The guy who sold us tickets wanted to put us on a boat which was apparently already full.
We just made it to walked around the pier to catch another one just&amp;nbsp;leaving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left town the following days in afternoon with a bus to La&amp;nbsp;Paz.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5557.jpg" alt="Lake Titicaca from Copacabana"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Lake Titicaca from Copacabana&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5566.jpg" alt="Copacabana"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Copacabana&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5579.jpg" alt="Lots of people come here for a ritual to protect themselves and their car on the road"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Lots of people come here for a ritual to protect themselves and their car on the road&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5585.jpg" alt="Offers for the cars &amp; people"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Offers for the cars &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; people&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5593.jpg" alt="Cathedral of Copacabana"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Cathedral of Copacabana&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5660.jpg" alt="Show in front of the Cathedral"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Show in front of the Cathedral&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5594.jpg" alt="Challapampa, Isla del Sol"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Challapampa, Isla del Sol&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5597.jpg" alt="Cordillera with some 7000m summits"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Cordillera with some 7000m summits&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5601.jpg" alt="Our hostel for the night, pretty new."/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Our hostel for the night, pretty new.&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5617.jpg" alt="Ridge trail on Isla del Sol"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Ridge trail on Isla del Sol&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5615.jpg" alt="Challa 1"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Challa 1&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5633.jpg" alt="Gorgeous view from Yumani, for our lunch!"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Gorgeous view from Yumani, for our lunch!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Arequipa &amp; Colca canyon</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2013/March/arequipa-colca-canyon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2013-03-23:2013/March/arequipa-colca-canyon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End of december&amp;nbsp;2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got on our first long distance bus travel, and a night trip to get to Arequipa from Lima. We
took the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VIP&lt;/span&gt; service to get the best seats, but still we could lay them all flat. Nevertheless
we got a nice service before and during the trip, with a diner and breakfast and movies. We had
the seats on the upper floor and in the first row to enjoy the view, but with more&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;turbulences&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Arequipa, we searched for information about the two canyons you can access in the region. We
tried to meet up with a guy from couchsurfing but it didn&amp;#8217;t work out. It&amp;#8217;s christmas time, busy time.
Thanks to the advice of the hostel&amp;#8217;s owner, we go on a roof terrace to look at the sunset the night
before leaving town. Amazing&amp;nbsp;spot!&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                         &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5101.jpg" alt="Arequipa cathedral with the surrounding mountains"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Arequipa cathedral with the surrounding mountains&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5087.jpg" alt="Apero time on the terrace thanks to the owner of our hostel!"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Apero time on the terrace thanks to the owner of our hostel!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We decided to see Colca canyon, but with our own means of transport and not on a tour from Arequipa.
They all looked pretty nasty when you looked at their time schedule with the tour leaving at 3am from Arequipa.
We took the
local bus to get to Cabanaconde and stay in a hostel there for one night before going in the canyon.
We arrived in the evening and the owner of the hostel was at the bus stop to pick us up, nice surprise!
Most people come with a tour, so if you want to have guest at your hostel without a paid reservation,
you&amp;#8217;d better be at the bus stop when they come, no? The guy was really nice, from the hostel Pachamama,
and gave us the information we needed about the canyon, which he does for anyone coming there.
So we had our plan for the following days and could enjoy a good pizza with&amp;nbsp;beers.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                         &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5133.jpg" alt="Local on our bus to Cabanaconde"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Local on our bus to Cabanaconde&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5140.jpg" alt="Ready to start the trek down the canyon"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Ready to start the trek down the canyon&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the morning we woke up to start walking down the canyon, much faster than we thought and we arrived
for an early lunch in the first village down on the other side of the river, San Juan de Chuccho. After chilling we walked
all the way up to Tapay, where we hoped to stay for the night but only the expensive lodge was open.
The owner of the other one was in Arequipa&amp;#8230; We learned this late in the afternoon, after waiting
for hours in front of the lodge and receiving fruits from a very old lady who could only speak Quechua.
We tried to ask her about the lodge but yeah, of course we didn&amp;#8217;t understand anything. When someone
else told us he was gone, we decided to go down to the village we would have passed by in the morning
for the night, Cosñirhua. We stayed in a posada with a group accompanied by a guide and had an excellent&amp;nbsp;diner.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5149.jpg" alt="Colca canyon trail"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Colca canyon trail&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span8"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5141.jpg" alt="Colca canyon from Cabanaconde side. Look at the trails. Tapay is the little grey T/X on the other side, quite high up."/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Colca canyon from Cabanaconde side.&lt;br/&gt;Look at the trails.                                 Tapay is the little grey T/X on the other side, quite high up in front. The river is also visible. Bigger than Grand Canyon, now way!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5150.jpg" alt="One of the few bridges over the river"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;One of the few bridges over the river&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5179.jpg" alt="Tapay's villagers working in their fields"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Tapay&amp;#8217;s villagers working in their fields&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5163.jpg" alt="An out-of-nowhere small park in Tapay, Cabanaconde is on the other side at the top"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;An out-of-nowhere small park in Tapay, Cabanaconde is on the other side at the top&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5181.jpg" alt="Waiting for the owner of the posada to show up. He never did!"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Waiting for the owner of the posada to show up. He never did!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5193.jpg" alt="Local help in the canyon!"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Local help in the canyon!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5197.jpg" alt="Sunset at Cosnirhua"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Sunset at Cosnirhua&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning we walked down to the other bridge, down the river, to cross back to Cabanaconde side,
and to chill out in what they call &amp;#8220;the oasis&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s very green, and with 5 posadas, each having its own
pool, with water coming from a source at a not too cold temperature. The water is flowing all the time so
no need for chlorine in the pool, nice! We had the pool for us as the tourist who are staying there are
always leaving early in the morning, and the next ones would only come after lunch. That was a great time!
Lunch in our stomach, we started the hike up the canyon to get back to the village and our hostel. Again,
the walk was faster than the time we got told from the hostel and it let us enjoy some beers in town before crawling
for a good night of&amp;nbsp;sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5200.jpg" alt="Oasis village"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Oasis village&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5211.jpg" alt="Pool of fresh water. The water is coming from a source, and goes back to the river."/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Pool of fresh water. The water is coming from a source, and goes back to the river.&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5222.jpg" alt="Confection of the dress."/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Confection of a dress.&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span12"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5223.jpg" alt="Cabanaconde"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Cabanaconde&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we took the bus back to Arequipa and a night bus to Cusco, our next&amp;nbsp;destination.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Lima, very short</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2013/March/lima-very-short.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2013-03-23:2013/March/lima-very-short.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Around Christmas&amp;nbsp;2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We landed in Lima on Christmas eve and had already booked a nice hotel for one night since
there wasn&amp;#8217;t any bus to travel to another town on the 24th. We arrived very early in the morning,
around 5.30am at the airport, and as well very early at the hotel. We had to wait for our room until 11am,
so we headed to the closest boulangerie to get a morning croissant and coffee. But yeah, again,
we had to wait, it was too early&amp;#8230; At least we could watched the locals, like runners, or Peruvians
selling cookies at traffic lights. When we got out of our morning break, we met the receptionist
of the hotel in the street on his way home and he let us knew that we could get the room right now.
Yes! Thank&amp;nbsp;you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our room, came a welcome drink, of course ;-) A pisco sour, the Peruvian drink! We took it
before our lunch, and it knocked us out I must say&amp;#8230; The barman maid it very strong (compared to
others we had&amp;nbsp;later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked in our neighborhood to find a restaurant and took a walking tour in the afternoon,
before heading back for some needed sleep. We tried to book a nice restaurant for our Christmas
diner but many places seemed to be closed for that evening so we just stayed in our hotel. The bed
was amazing and we had a great sleep! That was very well&amp;nbsp;welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after we procrastinated in our hotel room until we had to check-out. We walked through
another park to get our lunch and went to the bus terminal to catch our 6:30pm bus to&amp;nbsp;Arequipa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Lima time was more a resting time than a visiting one. Surely we missed some stuff,
but we kept our energy for later in&amp;nbsp;Peru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;         &lt;div class="span3 offset1"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                         &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/P1050779.jpg" alt="Waiting for the boulangerie to open"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Waiting for the boulangerie to open&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                         &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B5056.jpg" alt="First night bus of a long serie"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;First night bus of a long serie&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Jasper, Banff, Canmore, Waouw</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2013/February/jasper-banff-canmore-waouw.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2013-02-07:2013/February/jasper-banff-canmore-waouw.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whistler to Japser &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt; took us two full days. We played a bit more with the car
since we added the unpaved road as an option for the drive and yes, it made
us take some off-roads. But, nothing major as we had before in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;. We drove
through very nice landscapes with the autumn color. We found
good spots for the nights, and discovered as well how expensive two cappuccinos
and two pieces of cake could be&amp;#8230; It made us stop stoping for coffee and cake
for the rest of our trip, almost&amp;nbsp;;-)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span12"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1428.jpg" alt="Canadian landscapes, Green lake"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Canadian landscapes, Green lake&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1437.jpg" alt="Camping-car under the stars"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Camping-car under the stars&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1470.jpg" alt="Lake, red leafs, Canada!"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Lake, red leafs, Canada!&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We spent the second night just before entering Jasper &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt; as the weather was pretty
bad with snow coming. And anyway, it&amp;#8217;s better to spend one more free night outside
the park. The next morning we rolled down into Jasper and saw what mother nature
had created the day before with all those white trees everywhere, magical! But
it also meant for us, that we wouldn&amp;#8217;t be able to go hiking anywhere as pretty
much all the trails were covered with more than 10cm of snow the rangers told us and
we don&amp;#8217;t have winter&amp;nbsp;shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1532.jpg" alt="Jasper surroundings"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Jasper surroundings&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1533.jpg" alt="Jasper surroundings"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Jasper surroundings&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took the road to visit some of the lakes and enjoyed so much the scenery. Bears,
deers, moose, elks, &amp;#8230; Canadian&amp;nbsp;wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span9"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1565.jpg" alt="Medicine lake, Jasper NP"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Medicin lake, Jasper &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1728.jpg" alt="Maligne Lake, Jasper NP"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Maligne Lake, Jasper &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1738.jpg" alt="Maligne Lake, Jasper NP"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Maligne Lake, Jasper &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1666.jpg" alt="Not a fake one!"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Not a fake one!&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1701.jpg" alt="Moose on the dry part of Lake Medicin"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Moose on the dry part of Lake Medicin&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1787.jpg" alt="Jasper river?"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Jasper river?&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;div class="span3"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1648.jpg" alt="Big park bear"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Big park bear&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second night in the park, as we were driving South towards Banff, we wanted to
stay at another campground, even though it was below zero at night. All other
accommodations are very expensive. But the brochure didn&amp;#8217;t tell us that the only campsite
after the Glaciers was closed for maintenance work. We only saw a sign when we arrived at the entrance
telling us that the information is not in the brochure because it had been decided after printing it. Thank
you!
But they couldn&amp;#8217;t even tell you where is the next one open, no? Guys, there&amp;#8217;s miles
between each site, we&amp;#8217;re in the middle of the park! The hostel next door was charging
more than we would pay for a dorm without much electricity and bathrooms in another
building, meaning going out when it&amp;#8217;s freezing cold. So we used our imagination and decided to go for a good meal, well deserved,
in the expensive lodge of Mono lake, to warm up for the night at the same time. There,
we thought that no one would come to bother us if we hide and sleep somewhere on the
lodge&amp;#8217;s parking. And it worked very well, except that it&amp;#8217;s was freezing cold at night
and woke up with -10°C in the car before sunrise. Outside, it was even worse&amp;#8230; But the
scenery was worth the freezing toes to get those&amp;nbsp;shots.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1881.jpg" alt="Mono Lake, Jasper NP"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Mono Lake, Jasper &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span6"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1896.jpg" alt="Sunrise at Mono Lake, Jasper NP"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Sunrise at Mono Lake, Jasper &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we passed by Lake Louise, which was surprisingly almost completely closed for the
season. Only the big famous hotel was open for this lovely friday. What didn&amp;#8217;t I miss
when I came there 3 years ago to bike the great divide! We should have taken one more day
to visit those lakes with&amp;nbsp;Simon.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1958.jpg" alt="Moraine Lake, yeah!"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Moraine Lake, yeah!&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1995.jpg" alt="Perfect breakfast at Moraine Lake"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Perfect breakfast at Moraine Lake&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B2014.jpg" alt="Moraine Lake"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Moraine Lake&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B2036.jpg" alt="Lake Louise"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Lake Louise&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we had our most cosy stay with Rob and Ingrid, with their wonderful hospitality in
their bed and breakfast in Canmore, Cedar Springs. We spent one day in Banff, going back to the start
of the great divide trail, visiting town, and buying good wine. We celebrated with
Rob &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Ingrid and their friends the Canadian&amp;nbsp;thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Monday, we decided to leave, not because we didn&amp;#8217;t want to stay, but we had to
get South to visit the rest of the American National Parks. Glaciers had already
closed one pass and we couldn&amp;#8217;t drive through this one to get to Yellowstone, sadly,
as it&amp;#8217;s a very scenic drive we heard. Plenty of miles to drive before getting to Yellowstone,
so let&amp;#8217;s move&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B2041.jpg" alt="Lory, Rob, Ingrid and me at Cedar Springs B&amp;B"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Lory, Rob, Ingrid and me at Cedar Springs B&amp;B&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B2044.jpg" alt="Mountain goat"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Mountain goat&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B2055.jpg" alt="Dirt road down to Sparwood, AB"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Dirt road down to Sparwood, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B2060.jpg" alt="Reflection of the sky color in the river"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Reflection of the sky color in the river&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B2110.jpg" alt="Morning move, woop woop!"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Morning move, woop woop!&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B2126.jpg" alt="Ingrid's breakfast muffins, yumi!"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Ingrid&amp;#8217;s breakfast muffins, yumi!&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>British Columbia</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2013/February/british-columbia.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2013-02-06:2013/February/british-columbia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After those 3 days kayaking on Vancouver island, we had one wish: a hot shower! So we headed
pretty quickly to Vancouver to visit my cousin Samuel who moved there last September. The
cruise on the ferry in the late afternoon was amazing with the sunset while approaching the
city, and the sky changing colors. Moreover we would see the moon clearly over the city which
made a perfect welcoming for&amp;nbsp;us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail pull-right span3"&gt;         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1373.jpg"/ alt="Vancouver city at twilight"/&gt;         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Vancouver city at twilight&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We arrived at my cousin&amp;#8217;s place in Vancouver, at a very nice location I must say. And we rushed
for a first shower after those days kayaking. Samy did us a good diner, and his housemate gave
us his room for the 2 nights we stayed. Laundry, sleeping, emails, skype calls, chilling out&amp;#8230;
The time went very quickly and Saturday morning we were all 3 on our way to Whistler for a
week-end of biking. We stopped by (for quite a long time) at Mountain Coop to buy finally only
a few things, but warm, to survive the rest of our &amp;#8220;northern trip&amp;#8221;. It was beginning of October
and we still have a few hundreds kilometers to drive up North to&amp;nbsp;Jasper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Whistler, went around to decide where we would rent our moutain bikes, but the
place I knew was closed, with the SantaCruz&amp;#8217;s rental. So we ended with basic, simple bikes,
but enough for what we would do during 24h. We went with friends of my cousin for a little warm up
loop in the forest next to the parking, for them to know those very funny loops, and for Lory
to get used to her bike for the next riding&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met up with my friends Ignasi and Anni, who used to live in Whistler and just happened
to be there on holidays for one week. Perfect timing! We had diner and after went to see
two ski movies from Teton Gravity. As usually, a ski movie show doesn&amp;#8217;t come only with
movies, but with its set of give-aways / presents. Before entering the show, I saw we had
the tickets 213 and 214, and I don&amp;#8217;t really know why but I wanted to have the one finishing
with &amp;#8220;13&amp;#8221; that Lory had. So we swept them. We also put our names on small forms to win
different things during the evening, not knowing really what, but you know, it&amp;#8217;s all about
skiing, so it can only be good ;-)
At diner before, we were talking about luck, and Anni who uses to win almost all the time
something as Ignasi was telling us. And apparently her dad as well. So the lottery started to
give out the first most simple presents, and they were switching between picking a name
from the paper forms, or a ticket number for the night. And guess what, yes, Anni won a week ski
pass reduction. So, yes, it was true, she wins very often. Then they went on for a pair of
nice skis, big fatty one. And then they presented the ultimate present of the night, a
free heliski day in Haines, Alaska. They were gonna pick up a form, but many people
shouted to pick up a number. And here we go&amp;#8230;. Number &amp;#8220;213&amp;#8221;! I was pumped! I&amp;#8217;m really not
the usual winner as Anni. But I just got a free heliski day, one of my dream!
When we were watching the movies, I was thinking of myself, there in Alaska, as the movies were
about &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AK&lt;/span&gt;, skiing down those incredible steep slopes I&amp;#8217;ve always been dreaming of on my pair of tely&amp;#8230;. But it
will have to wait, too many travels&amp;nbsp;;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we went all together biking on some of the Whistler cross-country trails, and
had a good fun with the usual flats and other bike problems. Nevertheless I was happy
to bike again with Ignasi, Anni, Lory, Samy and all the others. My cousin had been living
in Vancouver for already one year, and he never went biking in Whistler. I couldn&amp;#8217;t let him
missed any longer what he already should have known for a long&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday morning, we were moving towards Jasper to see the National&amp;nbsp;Park.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span6 offset3"&gt;         &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span6"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/photo.jpg" alt="Bikers"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Bikers&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Visit to a dental clinic in Nicargua</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2012/December/visit-to-a-dental-clinic-in-nicargua.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2012-12-10:2012/December/visit-to-a-dental-clinic-in-nicargua.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Or should I start with another title more or less: what the f*ck did happen to Marco again?
It&amp;#8217;s not gonna be a long story with lots of blood or anything. It&amp;#8217;s pretty straight forward.
While I was surfing and trying to show something to Lory, I didn&amp;#8217;t think I was pretty close
to the beach and that the water was shallow. So when I fell from the board (because I&amp;#8217;m not
so good - and I won&amp;#8217;t get better anyway now&amp;#8230;) I went head first thinking I will make a
nice swim as I used to do when I was surfing in the bigger waves away from the beach. But
yes, as you can now imagine, it happened exactly as you&amp;#8217;re doing. I hit pretty hard my head
down on the sand (lucky enough there wasn&amp;#8217;t any rock!) and felt a strong shock in my neck
and a second one in my mouth! I recall that when I was still in the water I was already
seeing myself opening my mouth with a couple of loose pieces of teeth. Oh no! &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WTF&lt;/span&gt;! When
I got my head out of the water to breath, I let go my fear and checked what I could have
in my mouth&amp;#8230; Hhhmmm&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;. Nothing, or almost! I fell tiny pieces but nothing big. Oh
I&amp;#8217;m happy so far! Oh, but my neck! Achhh it&amp;#8217;s painful. I told Lory who was next to me that
I hit the bottom the hard way, as she could not have seen anything of what just&amp;nbsp;happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I showed her my teeth because I could feel a broken part in one of my incisive and, yes
there is something broken but it&amp;#8217;s not obvious. So now&amp;#8230; what next? Hmm? Well, it&amp;#8217;s me, so
let&amp;#8217;s go back surfing&amp;#8230; Not kidding! I went back but my back was really painful and I thought
like as in kitesurfing or skiing, it&amp;#8217;s when I&amp;#8217;m tired or have some pain in my muscles that
something worse can happen. So I stopped pretty quickly and went to rest on the beach.
My neck&amp;#8230; oh my neck&amp;#8230; the pain is really there and won&amp;#8217;t go away apparently this time!
Time for a beer to recover from my crash. But wait, isn&amp;#8217;t my teeth going to be super
sensitive now that it&amp;#8217;s broken on cold drinks? Let&amp;#8217;s try and see! Done is done, so let&amp;#8217;s
go for a first test. I take a small sip of beer, and another one, and another one, and
don&amp;#8217;t feel anything. Waaaououou! Later that night, I even tried a hot brownie with ice cream
and a cappuccino, and it was fine as&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after, Sunday, when I woke up, my neck &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; back were a mess&amp;#8230; :-( It wasn&amp;#8217;t a fun
day to spend and I played Robocop all day long. On Monday I found out that there was a
chiropractic guy in town and went directly there in the afternoon to be put back in place
or at least somehow, and hopefully to feel better quicker. And yes, it happened! The day
after I was better, even though I still had&amp;nbsp;pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened 2 weeks ago, and I still can&amp;#8217;t move freely my head without feeling some
pain in certain directions. So it will take a little while before I don&amp;#8217;t feel anything.
Nevertheless, during that time I went to the dentist and got my teeth&amp;nbsp;fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I did
go to the dentist in Nicaragua, at the Suncare dental clinic in town, in San Juan del Sur.
The guy was very
profesional and even showed my on a screen thanks to a little camera all my teeth and
cavities I had. It was the first time I saw so well all my teeth and inside my mouth! I
could see that his main topic is dental hygiene. A positive&amp;nbsp;experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I have to be careful with any shock and the future will tell me if I&amp;#8217;m a lucky
guy with really good teeth, or if the pair of cracks I have in each incisive teeth will
slowly expand or stay as they are&amp;#8230;&amp;nbsp;:-(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The finding out of this story&amp;#8230; I&amp;#8217;m done surfing I guess, not only because I&amp;#8217;ll be scare
to hit another time the bottom, but because I could experience already in Canada, Tofino,
that my broken cartilage ribs didn&amp;#8217;t healed correctly. More exactly, the cartilage didn&amp;#8217;t
consolidate as it was originally and now I have a piece of it pointing right out. And it
creates a big bruise right on the upper part of my stomach. Which doesn&amp;#8217;t let me surf
very long&amp;#8230; I said surfing, not kitesurfing, don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong here&amp;nbsp;;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;         &lt;div class="span4"&gt;         &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/IMG_1584.jpg" alt="My broken teeth"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;My broken teeth&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B4588.jpg" alt="Chiropractico, San Juan del Sur"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Chiropractico, San Juan del Sur&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B4596.jpg" alt="Suncare Dental Clinic San Juan Del Sur"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Suncare Dental Clinic, San Juan del Sur&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/IMG_1599.jpg" alt="Teeth fixed"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Teeth fixed&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vancouver Island</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2012/November/vancouver-island.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2012-11-20:2012/November/vancouver-island.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was starting to be the time to get to Canada to enjoy its landscape and outdoors before
the winter could arrive. So, first stop, was for the Vancouver island, and a famous place
called Tofino. My cousin, Samuel, was waiting for us to get there as he arrived early in
the morning, and more importantly to go surfing. No I&amp;#8217;m not kidding, even though it
can sound pretty cold: surfing + canada + pacific; it&amp;#8217;s exactly the first activity we did
there. Moreover it was super fun! Lory had her first surfing sessions, and really
enjoyed it. She didn&amp;#8217;t want to get out of the water. One good reason is that Tofino is
definitively a good spot to begin surfing, and also for advanced surfers if the swell is
big. We all had a lot of fun, and were exhausted by the end of the evening. We stayed
in the water until the sunset&amp;nbsp;:-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guest what, after&amp;#8230; Time to find some food for those empty and hungry people. Tacotofino
was closed, hummmm, too late! The next stop, supermarket, closed as well. Hmmm&amp;#8230; Finally
we found food at the convenience store for a simple but big diner, that Samy and Nigel
had to cook before they were closing the kitchen of the hostel (11pm). Which they just did
in time! Diner at 11:30pm, a long day since our wakeup at 6am to catch the&amp;nbsp;ferry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning we slept in a bit, since we had a proper bed since many days, and went
back to the beach for more surfing. It was fun to go surfing with my cousin. I&amp;#8217;m used to
got snowboarding with him, and that was a nice change. And that day, we got to eat my
cousin&amp;#8217;s best known tacos. And it&amp;#8217;s true, it was delicious after a long day surfing to
have such a&amp;nbsp;meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After surfing, Lory had seen before that Vancouver island was also famous for the
possibility of seing orcas (killer whales) in its northern part. We jumped in the car and
went off for more miles to rent a kayak in one of the last place still open, some food
and headed to Naka creek to launch our double sea-kayak. We slept in the car at the
launching site and were welcome with &amp;#8220;Bear&amp;#8221; - the dog ;-) A couple of canadian are living
down there, Bonnie and Ed, year around&amp;#8230; It&amp;#8217;s a good 30 minutes drive to their mailbox
on the main road. I guess they must have a skidoo for the winter time to get &amp;#8220;out&amp;#8221;. Anyway,
after talking with Ed and giving some information regarding rescue and were we planned
to paddle, we carried our heavy packed kayak to the water. Time was moving, but not us, and
we hoped to paddle quite a bit that same day. Now what, hummm, the water is still very cold
and there isn&amp;#8217;t any other kayak, neither many boats on the water. So rule #1: it&amp;#8217;s
absolutely forbidden to fall in the water! Our spot device is on to track our progress, so
let&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We crossed the Johnstone straight to get on the other side so that we would be already
on the side where we could camp. After battling a bit against the wind, we set up the
lunch camp onto a small rock, energy was needed for both of us! After paddling, and
paddling, and more paddling, we started to see some &amp;#8220;shapes&amp;#8221; coming out on the surface!
Waoup woup&amp;#8230; what is it? Me: Orcas??? Lory: Hmmm I don&amp;#8217;t think, it looks pretty small.
Me: but it&amp;#8217;s far away&amp;#8230;?? The sun was starting to decline already enough to think more
about a night camp, than the orcas, if we wised to have a cozy night somehow&amp;#8230; on rocks!
We found a good camp site mark on the map, which is a &amp;#8220;must-have&amp;#8221; map, just because of the
camp sites which are scare. We had a couple of seals coming to check us out, wondering
what the heck we were doing here that late maybe. Camp set up, kayak high enough on the
rocks so that it should still be there in the morning, otherwise we&amp;#8217;re going to be stuck
in the middle of the straight on a tiny island, with almost no boats passing by. But then
you remember after diner, that you&amp;#8217;re still in Canada, a country known for theirs bears.
Well don&amp;#8217;t forget to attach your food somehow high enough in a tree, because they can
swim! And we just had some tuna&amp;#8230;. As usual from my experience, we only found tree
branches that didn&amp;#8217;t fit the how-you-should-hang-your-food bears&amp;nbsp;guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning we had the good surprise to see our food still hanging in one pice of bag
in that tree, so let&amp;#8217;s enjoy a good breakfast! Eating, cleaning, packing and loading the
kayak before paddling to maybe see orcas&amp;#8230; Again I start to see some shapes coming out
of the water and discuss the point with Lory, although it&amp;#8217;s far away I still seemed to
be wrong. But we heard after that some strangeeee noises. We sought around us, but there
was nothing. Some times later, ohhhhh ahhhhh we can see some water splashing out of a
marine moving creature! There seems to be at least 2 orcas other there&amp;#8230; there, pretty
far away&amp;#8230; Lory started like: of orcas!!! Look! Wouaww&amp;#8230;. hmmmm, but an orca is big,
right? And there&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8230; not a single boat, neither kayak, neither anything in any
viewable distance from us, only very cold water. Heuuhhh&amp;#8230; what we do now? Me, of course:
let&amp;#8217;s go and get closer to them. I started to paddle right away, all excited, but Lory
was: beuuh beuh you&amp;#8217;re sure? We&amp;#8217;re alone? Do you think it&amp;#8217;s a good idea? They are way
bigger than us, you know!&amp;#8230; What would happen if? The thing is that the orcas breath
a couple of times and then go deep for quite a long time. So by the time we started they
were gone. Anyway we were heading in their direction. They came out again, and were still
far from us, but going in our direction, against us. Let&amp;#8217;s keep that direction! Again
we were seeking them and wondering where they could come out while we stopped paddling.
And then, then, I heard a &amp;#8220;big-splash&amp;#8221; at the same time as I was looking at the first
one coming out. I could only say one word: Hmmmmmmmmmmmmmmaaaaaaaaaa! (while breathing
in - try it!). I guess Lory was more surprised by the sound out of my mouth than the orcas
being at 400 meters form us. That became &amp;#8220;marco the orca&amp;#8221; ;-) Even though I had the camera
between my legs in the kayak, I was just staring at them and enjoying their little
come out and come in. Ops,they&amp;#8217;re gone now! Let&amp;#8217;s not move and see where they will come
out next, as it shouldn&amp;#8217;t be far away from us &amp;#8220;maybe&amp;#8221;&amp;#8230; camera in the hands. And
later, again, but way further than I thought, they came out.
We saw them again a few times, but always much further away from us each time. At least
we had to see them alone, in the middle of the straight! Amazing! That was the dessert,
served before lunch: the tide was going down, so the water was getting out of the straight
but we had to go in the opposite direction. A good challenge for us for the next 6 hours
until we found a camp for the night, just before we had to get out our headlamps. Still,
we weren&amp;#8217;t so close of the launching site, so we woke up early in the morning and
paddled for other an hour and a half until we arrived back to the car and could have a
breakfast! Our kayak trip was over, we were both glad for being able to see orcas, and
to have 3 clear blue sky days on the&amp;nbsp;straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the smelly couple had to go a get a shower in Vancouver (the city)&amp;#8230; our next&amp;nbsp;stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;         &lt;div class="span4"&gt;         &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1178.jpg" alt="Black Bell ferry"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Black Bell ferry&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1190.jpg" alt="Tofino hostel"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Coffee time at Tofino hostel&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1216.jpg" alt="Kayak is loaded and ready to go"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Kayak is loaded and ready to go&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;         &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1245.jpg" alt="Still there!"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Still there!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1223.jpg" alt="Johnstone straight"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Johnstone straight&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1235.jpg" alt="Camp site #1"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Camp site #1&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1255.jpg" alt="Good morning!"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Good morning!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1272.jpg" alt="Orcas!"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Orcas!&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>West coast road trip, a beginning</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2012/October/west-coast-road-trip-a-beginning.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2012-10-22:2012/October/west-coast-road-trip-a-beginning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time to leave Truckee, time to get used to our new car and to find a good set-up in it
for the bags and most importantly, our bed. First, some mileages.. The car is super easy to
drive and we bought 2 audio books to get us through our too many hours of driving we
have ahead of us. We bought the Night Circus (really good) and The Help (haven&amp;#8217;t started
it yet). And no Francis (I hope he will recognize himself), the car isn&amp;#8217;t a fuel
s*cker, we got to an average of 19 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MPG&lt;/span&gt; (12.7 L/100km) at some point, which is not too bad
for a V6 motor and heavy car. The roads are wide and without much traffic. We also enjoy
the satellite radio&amp;nbsp;;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did we first headed? Avenue of the Giants, south of Redwood, in California. First we
were supposed to meet up with Ciara but it didn&amp;#8217;t work, sadly. We went on our own to see
those first big trees. Wide and tall!! I didn&amp;#8217;t try to estimate the number of matches
you can get out of such a tree&amp;#8230; maybe billions! Some of them are big enough to hold you
inside them. Others can get through a car, not our&amp;#8217;s of&amp;nbsp;course&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;         &lt;div class="span4"&gt;         &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span3"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0552.jpg" alt="Avenue of the Giants, CA"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Avenue of the Giants, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;/ul&gt;         &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt;         &lt;div class="span12"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we had to find a spot for another night and we cruised to find something close to the Ocean. Of
course in the morning we went to check out how cold the Ocean was&amp;#8230; Brrrrr it&amp;#8217;s cold! And it&amp;#8217;s cloudy,
so it doesn&amp;#8217;t make it&amp;nbsp;warmer&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we went to see Redwood National Park. Again, some gigantic trees, even taller than in Phillipsville.
We look very very&amp;nbsp;small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nights in the car were starting to be kind of painful. We would woke up in the morning partly
with a broken back. We started to sleep on our inflatable mattress but they were pretty noisy.
Nevertheless we were still very happy to be free and able to camp where ever we wanted. Anything
has to have it down&amp;nbsp;sides&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next Park on the list was Crater Lake. I still think that Lake Tahoe is an amazing lake. But this one,
is incredible. Its color is a perfect deep blue. Best of all, is the way you get there. Having in its
name the word &amp;#8220;crater&amp;#8221;, you get there by climbing an easy road, and all the sudden you see this
beautiful lake out of nowhere.
I couldn&amp;#8217;t resist to get down on its cliffs to get some better shots even though Lory wasn&amp;#8217;t so
happy reading signs everywhere about dangerous cliffs and falls. But it was worth it :) We spent
a couple of hours enjoying its scenery from different point of views. I&amp;#8217;ll let you anjoy a few&amp;nbsp;photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop on the road trip, Portland! There, we were welcome by Megan and Charly. We headed straight
to the pub for some happy hours beers &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; food. Thanks to them and their friends, we got some good
tips for future parts of our road trips in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;. One very good we got the day after before leaving
from Mega was the location of a fabric store where we bought foam blocks to create a nice bed in
the trunk of the car. That was some well spent &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; dollars! We spent actually the day going around
shops to buy stuff we wanted for our big trip as in Oregon state there is no sale taxe. In
the evening we left Portland, in the direction of Olympic National&amp;nbsp;Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped along the road on a fresh &amp;#8220;man built&amp;#8221; village, in the middle of nowhere, Seabrook. It feels
really strange to see such a thing. It&amp;#8217;s like being in a movie where they just created a
small town for an horror movie&amp;#8230; Everything looks new, everyone is smiling. If you go around
the corner, you see that there&amp;#8217;s nothing more, just the forest. People are getting a speech
(I guess) about how wonderful it will be to live here and that they should buy a property. And
looking closer to the houses, they all look&amp;nbsp;empty&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I thought it woud be fun to get some unpaved road done, so let&amp;#8217;s go and cut a stretch we
have to do to reach the coast&amp;#8230; It got very tight, even too tight at the end and we took another
road to escape this forest. We drove on very tiny bridges, which we hoped would hold the weight
of the&amp;nbsp;car&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next morning, we took the ferry to get to Victoria, on Vancouver Island. Canada! Time
for the maple sirup, moose and cooler temperature. First let&amp;#8217;s go to Tofino, where my cousin
Samy is waiting on us to go surfing&amp;#8230; Surfing?? Really? In this cold&amp;nbsp;water?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now, place to the photos what can speak better than words sometime to describe our&amp;nbsp;trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt; &lt;div class="span12"&gt; &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0618.jpg" alt="It's cold!"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;It&amp;#8217;s cold!&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0721.jpg" alt="Klamath coast, CA"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Klamath coast, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0912.jpg" alt="Hopworks Urban Brewery, Portland, OR"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Hopworks Urban Brewery, Portland, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span6"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0690.jpg" alt="Redwood NP"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Redwood &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt; - Find Lory!&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span6"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1158.jpg" alt="Olympic NP"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Olympic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0944.jpg" alt="Spooky SeaBrook"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Spooky Seabrook&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0963.jpg" alt="Having fun!"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Having fun!&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B1080.jpg" alt="Off roads..."/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Off roads&amp;#8230;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span12"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0763.jpg" alt="Crater Lake, OR"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Crater Lake, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Californian landing</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2012/October/californian-landing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2012-10-19:2012/October/californian-landing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here we are on the plane, getting close to land to San Francisco, and I should be thinking that
our trip has finally started. But no, I just watched the kitesurfers along the bay riding, and
feeling that I was just landing to one of my numerous &amp;#8220;home&amp;#8221; in the world. I mean somewhere where
I&amp;#8217;ve been often enough to feel like home. Anyway, it was only the beginning of our adventures, no
more Europe for a certain time, let&amp;#8217;s get this rental car and start the road&amp;nbsp;trip!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rental car, yes I can call it &amp;#8220;The&amp;#8221; car we finally got after 3 hours at the counter&amp;#8230; The
guy tried to persuade us to get another type of car because in my opinion I did the mistake
telling him we will sleep in the car. So we saw different car and being told that there
wasn&amp;#8217;t any Chevy Tahoe left at the airport (apparently). But after discussions, and him getting
tired I guess as well, we got The car and. He made us pay for some extra stuff which were included in our booking
since he wanted to go home and not to redo all the typing in his computer. He even left us
with the keys of another car we said we didn&amp;#8217;t want. So yeah, after 3 hours we were finally getting
a large &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SUV&lt;/span&gt; as we wanted, to have space in the trunk to sleep and have our bags, even though
it will consume quite a lot of fuel. We ended up with a Ford Expedition.
After an incredibly &amp;#8220;hard to focus&amp;#8221; drive to Truckee, with my eyes and brain trying to go to sleep
due to the jetlag and 2 previous short nights, and not much sleep on the plane, we were welcome
by Greg who stood late for us. Finally, we could sleep, thank&amp;nbsp;you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent 3 days in Truckee, to go around Lake Tahoe, chill out on Donner lake, do some shopping in Reno for the road trip
and to see some friends, or to surprise others who weren&amp;#8217;t aware of our visit.
We tried hard to get a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIM&lt;/span&gt; card that we could also
use as a 3G hotspot during the road trip, but there&amp;#8217;s simply nothing to do both in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;. And the 3G
cards are kind of expensive. Eventually we decided not to get one, and only use a few times our
Swiss phones, and the free wifi we will find along the&amp;nbsp;road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we had in mind to get a Chevy Tahoe, we tried to exchange our car at Reno airport, but the guy
had only a simple truck left for the night&amp;#8230; No luck for now!
The reason is that the back seats don&amp;#8217;t fold as flat in the Expedition as in the Tahoe&amp;#8230; But we&amp;#8217;ll try
at another location to exchange&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="span4"&gt;         &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;                 &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                         &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                                 &lt;img src="/static/pictures/P1050243.jpg" alt="Going board paddling on Donner lake"/&gt;                                 &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Going board paddling on Donner lake&lt;/div&gt;                         &lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="row"&gt; &lt;div class="span12"&gt; &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0511.jpg" alt="Emerald bay, Lake Tahoe, CA"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Emerald bay, Lake Tahoe, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0509.jpg" alt="Driving around..."/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Driving around in our &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SUV&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/GX1B0524.jpg" alt="Erin, William and little Layne"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Erin, William and little Layne.&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Last minute rush</title><link href="http://come-away-with.me/2012/September/last-minute-rush.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Marc-Aurèle</name></author><id>tag:come-away-with.me,2012-09-13:2012/September/last-minute-rush.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So here we are, finally, on our flight cross the atlantic! But before that, we had to get ready, which means to finish
a lot of things. Last Friday was my last day at work after an intense week trying to organize a few last things, buying
some gears we need, selling my mountain bike, thinking about what to take for the trip&amp;#8230; Still after the week-end visiting
Lory&amp;#8217;s parent we weren&amp;#8217;t close to be ready in any point of view. Wednesday lunch time was our deadline, that was sure! But
before that we had to sort out our multiple paperwork, to bring my car and scooter to different friends, to say
goodbye to a few last friends, to pack down all my belongings moving them in the basement, giving the
keys to the new renters, &amp;#8230; By wednesday 5am (5 in the morning!) we were close to the end of our &amp;#8220;must&amp;#8221; to-do list, as much
as ourselves, and crashed in bed for a 2 hours power night/nap, as you want, but not much anyway&amp;#8230; And to awaken to start
the cleaning of the flat. At lunch time, we could rest to enjoy a last glass of wine and be delighted of that was left ahead
of us: 12 months round the world to visit our short-list of countries. Still it was hard to feel that we were on holidays, still
seing familiar walls, building and&amp;nbsp;streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clock is ticking, wake up! Time to move to the train station, to catch an early train and get on a first destination, London.
But wait, who just poped out at the same time of his door as we were closing our, my neighbour Bruno (another round world
class traveler). As he said, he had the extrem pleasure to share the first meters of a round world trip, to be the first encounter
we did on our journey ;-) Thanks Bruno for those minutes. I&amp;#8217;m sure that plans of new adventures are shacking and shaping in his
mind right&amp;nbsp;now&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For once we had time, we weren&amp;#8217;t gonna rush to the airport and into the plane. That&amp;#8217;s not as you want to start such a trip. But that
was without reaching the huge queue we had to get through in the middle of a wednesday afternoon at Geneva airport. What the heck
were doing all those people getting on an Easyjet flight? But well, we had 1.5 hours ahead of us, it should be enough, right?
We didn&amp;#8217;t reach the end of the queue that people of our flight to
Gatwick were pleased to jump into dedicated counters to register quickly their luggages as we had about 40 minutes left before
the flight due departure time. Guess what, even if it went quite smoothly, the next challenge was to get through the security
check with those other wednesday-middle-afternoon-people who wanted to take a plane&amp;#8230; Soon 15 minutes left before departure
and we weren&amp;#8217;t really close to the scanner. I don&amp;#8217;t want to miss our first flight, come&amp;#8217;on! Excuse me Sir, would you mine to let
us jump in front of you? We might have 5 minutes left to get on our flight&amp;#8230; Yeeees, he let us go. Bags, belts, computers on the
scanner belt, pants in one hand, smile on the face, everything is fine, no biping. Let&amp;#8217;s rush to the gate noooooow!!! No one left seating in
the waiting area, and they were calling for boarding the last passengers. Check! Touch down! Whatever you want, but we were in! :-)
60 seconds later we were already sitting in a row, hearing that we were closing the plane door. Ouch! What a&amp;nbsp;start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of minutes later we had our last sight of Switzerland until a long time, the adventure was on! And the surprises as well.
We landed in time in Gatwick, but it was without the idea that another flight from Amsterdam landed 3 minutes before us with my
sister in it. We arrived at the bagages claim and Lory saw directly her pimped bright flashy yellow protecting cover rolling in
front of passengers. She left me, and like 5 seconds later while I was cruising up the bags belt my eyes, someone grabbed me by
the shoulder. What? Is there a good friend here at the same time? Who is it? I turned my head around to meet my sister smiling!
Wouaw! She came all the way from Holland to spend the evening with us and our cousins for a last goodbye. Then my aunt was waiting
for us with big open arms and huge smile seing all of us coming together.
We spend a great evening chatting with Simon, with who I crossed the Rockies from North to South on a mountain bike in 2009,
Marina &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Luke, and Tim. Time was flying and our next flight was approaching. Another short night of not even 5 hours before
Evelyne kindly dropped us at Heathrow for our flight to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SFO&lt;/span&gt;. Oh surprise&amp;#8230; No queue!!! And more than 2 hours before our flight.
We got on the plane easily, with time for a breakfast before&amp;nbsp;hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I can say: what a&amp;nbsp;start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="span4"&gt; &lt;ul class="thumbnails"&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/IMG_1495.jpg" alt="bags are ready"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Bags are ready.&lt;/div&gt;                 &lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/P1050219.jpg" alt="Surprise at the airport!"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Surprise at the airport!&lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt;         &lt;li class="span4"&gt;                 &lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;                         &lt;img src="/static/pictures/P1050232.jpg" alt="Coding in the plane"/&gt;                         &lt;div class="caption"&gt;Coding in the plane&amp;#8230;&lt;/div&gt;         &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>